(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T13:34:09.054214",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
まあるいのどからちゅっとしちゃえ
From your round throat, let's just slurp it down!
全然「無理」思っちゃうし
I keep thinking "There's no way,"
だってだって不安になるし
but you know, I get so anxious.
全然嘘つけないし
I can't tell lies at all,
だってだってバカまっすぐだし
and you know, I'm just way too straight-forward.
目指すキラキラもっとぼく次第だ
The sparkle I aim for depends more on me!
ピター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
Bitter? I'm never going to say I give up!
じっとしてらんないし
I can't just stay still,
だってだって動いちゃう脚
because you know, my legs just start moving!
1、1、ステップアップちょっとずつ進めば夢の式とけちゃうの
Step by step, advancing little by little, the formula of dreams will melt away!
なりたいぼくをきみが好きなぼくを
The "me" I want to be, the "me" you love—
ちゃんと余りなく見せたいの今
I want to show you all of it right now without holding back!
あっちゃっちゃびっくりするほどできないじゃん
Oh no, I'm surprisingly bad at this, aren't I?
間違って悩んだりばっかじゃん
Making mistakes and just worrying all the time.
けどきみに見つけてほしくて
But because I want you to find me,
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ出会えたんならハッピー
I'm going to go greet you—if we can meet, it's happy!
泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
Crying, crying, loving, wagging my tail,
だめなぼくをどうか覚えておいて
please remember this clumsy me!
もうきみののどからちゅっとしちゃえ
From your throat, let's just slurp it down!
うっかりかとうれいがい まな歩いて尻に当たるの
Accidentally, miraculously, a wise walk leads right into it...
どんわんステップアップ
Come on, step up!
病んだふりしてるのやめて
Stop pretending to be depressed.
はいいこっちおいで
Hey, come over here!
出たがりきみと はげすぎなぼくとで
With you, who loves the spotlight, and me, trying too hard,
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go even further.
あっつあつびっくりするほどできないじゃん
It's so hot and surprisingly impossible,
間違って悩んでばかりじゃん
Just making mistakes and worrying all the time.
けどきみに出つけてほしくて
But I wanted you to find me,
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
So I'm going to meet you—if we meet, it's happy!
だってやっぱりひとりじゃダメだけど
'Cause being alone is no good,
集まってばかりじゃしてはわっちゃえば
But if we just gather and break through,
ほらいつでも言える「おかえり」
See, I can always say "Welcome back."
ぼくはきみに伝えたいんだ 大いなるハッピー
I want to tell you: a grand happy!
わーおわーお 叫んじゃえ
Wow-wow, just shout it out!
泣いてないで 愛して尻尾振って
Don't cry, love me and wag your tail!
わーおわーお 叫んじゃえ
Wow-wow, just shout it out!
だめなぼくをどうか覚えておいて
Please remember this useless me.
目指すキラキラもっとほくしだいだ
Aiming for sparkle depends even more on me!
ビター？キープアップなんて言わないんだ
Bitter? I won't say "keep up."
加速メラメラぶっちぎり次第だ
Speeding up with blazing flames depends on blowing past!
はぐれずに希望へと大暴走
Wildly rushing toward hope without getting lost.
きみのことこちくっとしちゃって
Making you feel all tickled,
いいじゃんハッピーじゃん
Isn't that great? Isn't that happy?
あーはい！みなさんこんばんはー！
Ah, yes! Good evening, everyone!
ホロライブロックの、ロックの頭脳！白衣こよりだよー！
Hologram Rock's brain, Hakui Koyori!
本日1月28日に白衣こより1周年を迎えました！やったー！やったー！
Today, January 28th, marks my 1st anniversary as Hakui Koyori! Yay! Yay!
ちょっと息切れてますけれども
I'm a little out of breath, but...
1曲目はですね、デコニーナさんに作っていいただきました！こよの初めてのオリジナルの曲わおをお聴きいただきました！
The first song was made for me by Dekonina-san! You just listened to Koyori's very first original song, "Wao!"!
どうだった？どうだったかな？あー！
How was it? How did you like it? Ah!
コメントもほいといっぱい！盛り上がってもらってありがとう嬉しい！
Keep the comments coming! Thank you so much for getting hyped, I'm so happy!
え、ハッシュタグはですね、白衣こより1周年でやっておりますので、え、Twitterでもね、いっぱい呟いて盛り上げていって下さいお願いしますー！
Um, the hashtag is #HakuiKoyori1stAnniversary, so please tweet a lot on Twitter to hype it up, I'm counting on you!
というわけで、今日はこの1年の集大成というわけで、こよりらしさをいっぱい詰め込んだ、ざ、こよりの1時間を準備しました！
So, today we've prepared an hour of pure "Koyori-ness," packed to the brim as the culmination of this past year!
最後の最後までおしらせやひらめきいっぱいあるので、ライブが終わってぐるぐるぐるってなるまで見ていってください！
There will be lots of announcements and brainstorming all the way until the end, so please keep watching until the live is completely over!
それじゃあ、次にするのは…
Now then, next up is...
配信を続行できません
[System Error: Cannot continue broadcast]
え、どういうことですカー！？
Eh, what is the meaning of this?!
なんかラボに戻されてるし、手錠手錠ついてるんですけど！
Somehow I'm back in the lab, and I've got handcuffs on!
え、今日こよ1周年なんですよ！？告知もいっぱいあるんで、こんなことしてる場合じゃないんですが！
Wait, today is Koyori's 1st anniversary?! There are so many announcements, this is no time for this!
助手君と協力して試練を乗り越えろ！？えー試練ってどういうことですか？あ、もう1枚ある、もう1枚？
"Work with Assistant-kun to overcome the trials"?! Eh, what does "trial" mean? Ah, there's another card, another one?
え、試練 謎を解いて歌声を届けよう え、何？まるまるまるを使え まるまるまるになれ まるまるまる、最後何もわかんない
Eh, Trial: "Solve the riddle and deliver your singing voice." Eh, what? "Use [___], become [___], [___]..." I have no idea at the end.
この謎を解いて、あ、わかったこより！頭脳ですからね、これは、この曲をこれに沿った曲を3曲歌えば試練クリアってことじゃないですか？
Solve this riddle—ah, I got it, Koyori! Since I'm a brain, if I sing three songs fitting this riddle, the trial is cleared, right?
ということですよねたぶんね！というわけでじゃあ、これからこよりこの謎を解いて3曲当てようと思いますので
That must be it! So, I'm going to solve this riddle and guess 3 songs from now on,
あの助手君コメントで一緒に謎を解いてください！
So Assistant-kun, please help me solve the riddle in the comments!
ちょっと待ってこれ、なんかちょっとエッチじゃない？え、こんなことしてる場合じゃない！では1曲目、1曲目の謎を解きたいと思います。脳みそありがとね！
Wait a second, isn't this a bit lechi (ecchi)? Eh, this is no time for this! Now, I'd like to solve the riddle for the first song. Thanks, brain!
1曲目の謎、これです！
The riddle for the first song is this!
は、なんだ？あ、あ、簡単なんだよねこれわ！ちょっとこより謎ね、あの、得意なんで待って。でもえ、類
Ha, what? Ah, it's an easy riddle, right? Koyori is good at riddles, so wait. But, eh, Rui-
ぺこら先輩！ぺこらこれ名前が出るんじゃないかなって思ったんだけど、なんでこよりは4文字なの？こよりこよりやろ！どうして？
Pekora-senpai! Pekora, I thought her name would come up, but why is Koyori 4 characters? Koyori Koyori, right? Why?
で、こうあみだくじで辿っていった先の、あの、出てくる文字でしょ。だからこう戻ってみよう123つっつっつっつっつ…
And then, the characters that come out at the end of following the Amidakuji (ghost leg). So let's try going back: 1, 2, 3, tsu-tsu-tsu-tsu...
あ！ぺこら先輩の「ら」になったから、「ら」！で、え、つっつっつっつ…
Ah! It became Pekora-senpai's "ra," so "ra"! And, eh, tsu-tsu-tsu...
るいろえの「る」になったから、えっと、「る」？何？「る」？で、こうちゃちゃちゃちゃちゃちゃちゃちゃ…って行くから、ちょっと待って白衣こよりは何で4文字なんだ？
It became Luire's "ru," so um, "ru"? What? "ru"? And then it goes cha-cha-cha... wait, why is Hakui Koyori 4 characters?
あ、あ、あ待って！あ、分かったかもしれない！あ、ちょっとみんなも書いてくれてるじゃん、そうか！
Ah, ah, ah wait! Ah, I might get it! Ah, everyone is writing it in the comments, right!
高うさぎ小代ってじゃあ、みんなの方が
So "Taka-usagi Koyori," everyone was
早かったか。こよリもさ、今こよかな？とかちょっと思ったんだけど
faster? I actually thought about "Kon-Koyori" too...
高うさぎ小代ってことは、えっと
But if it's "Taka-usagi Koyori," then um...
ぺこら先輩の義うさぎの義に1文字目が行ったから義！
The first character comes from Pekora-senpai's "Gi-usagi," so "Gi"!
類々が「たか」だから、「た」に行ったから「た」！
And "Rui-rui" is "Taka," so it went to "Ta," making "Ta"!
で、小代が「こようて」だから、3文字目に上がっていったから、伸ばせばギターを使え！だよ！
And "Koyori" is "Koyote," going up 3 characters, so if you stretch it out, it's "Play the guitar!"
なんかすげぇ大王を使え、大王を使えはおかしいやろ！
Wait, "Use the Great King"? That makes no sense!
なんか、神聖原始みたいな使わなきゃいけないやろ。ギターイエーイ！
You gotta use something like "Sacred Primitive." Guitar, yay!
じゃあ2曲目！2曲目の謎もください。おね,これね、あのこれが解けねえと押すんですよ今日。
Now for song #2! Please give me the second riddle. If I can't solve this, I have to press it today.
もうマジでこれが不安だった。はい、くださいください。2本目どうぞ！
I was honestly so worried about this. Yes, please! Here's the second one!
カリウム＋E＋モリブデン＋窒素＋酸素＝？
Potassium + E + Molybdenum + Nitrogen + Oxygen = ?
あ、でもね、ちょっとこれ、これはちょっと小代リよ、何だと思っているのか、このラボを見てね、
Ah, but you know... what does Koyori think this is? Look at this lab,
繋がってんな！研究、研究者ですからね。これはあれなんじゃねえの、あの、あ、あ、待って、なんか後ろに
it's all connected! I'm a researcher, after all. Isn't this like... wait, behind me...
え、元素、え、元素表なくても解けるって。ちょっと待って、元素表、
Wait, you can solve it without a periodic table? Hold on, periodic table...
元素表、周期表か。周期表なくても解ける。そう、カリウムはK。
Periodic table, right. You can solve it without one. Right, Potassium is K.
ね、カリウムはKだから、K、E、モリブデン何みんな？MB？
Right, Potassium is K, so K, E, Molybdenum is what, everyone? MB?
MB？M、あ、MO、MO！え、窒素はN、酸素はO。
MB? M, ah, MO, MO! Nitrogen is N, Oxygen is O.
これ付いてきてますか、皆さん？結構コメント欄解けてますね。
Are you guys following along? The chat is solving it pretty well.
というわけで、K、E、MO、NOだから、ケモノ！やったー！
So, K, E, MO, NO makes... "Kemono"! Yay!
ライナク優しくね、周期表なんて用意してくれてたけど、女子君がいればね、もうすぐ分かっちゃいますよ。小代も、ま、小代も分かってましたけどね、別に。あ、モリブデンMO、わか、分かってましたけどね。
Line-aku was so nice preparing a periodic table, but with Joshi-kun here, we figured it out right away. Well, Koyori already knew too, you know. Ah, Molybdenum MO, I-I knew that too, of course.
それでは3本目ください！
Now please give me the third one!
ちょっ、これ、あれ何々？タバタバ、タバタバじゃなくて、タバタタ、タバタタ！天才ありがとう。タバタタって何？
Wait, what's this? "Taba-taba"—no, not "Taba-taba," "Tabata-ta, Tabata-ta!" Genius, thanks. What is "Tabata-ta"?
タバタタ（笑）声に出して言いたくなる日本語、タバタタ。え？
Tabata-ta (laughs). Japanese you just want to say out loud: Tabata-ta. Huh?
で、試験管に、入ってんね。紫、オレンジ、グリーン、赤、緑、赤みたいな。
And there are test tubes. Purple, orange, green, red, green, red, or something.
手錠は、ありよ。手錠、方々繋がってるから今ガシャガシャガシャガシャガシャ。音聞こえる？ガシャガシャガシャガシャ。
There are handcuffs. The handcuffs are connected all over, so clank clank right now. Can you hear the sound? Clank clank.
え、え、これ何？みんな分かる？タバタタ。たばか。タバタあの日本、日本のね、東京にあるたば、たばこなわけじゃない。
Huh, what's this? Do you guys get it? Tabata-ta. Tabaka. Tabata, it's not like the Tabata in Tokyo, Japan.
すごく、分からない間、ちょっとセクシーなポーズをして、あ、手錠釣るようにやってもらえるといいんじゃないですかね。あ、こうやってね。あ、あ、なんて、女子君と耐えないで、うーん。
While I don't know, maybe I'll strike a sexy pose, like hanging by the handcuffs. Like this. Ah, ah, why, don't just endure it with Joshi-kun, ugh...
え、何？これ。あ、みんなちょっと待って、天才じゃん。飛び立て、ちょっとこれもう答えいっちゃった。みんなが解くの早すぎてそのままで答え読んじゃったよ。分かった！
Huh, what? This. Ah, everyone wait, you guys are geniuses. "Fly away"—wait, I already gave away the answer! Everyone solved it so fast I ended up reading the answer. I get it!
、あの、解き方分かった、解き方！えっと、これは、た行、ば行、た行、た行ってことで、
I figured out how to solve it! Um, it's the "ta" row, "ba" row, "ta" row, "ta" row,
で、そのあいうえおってこう、あいうえおをご、5個あるから、たの5個目、の5個目までですかね、こう、あの、入ってないからね、液体のね。
and since there are 5 vowels, it's the 5th one of the "ta" row, up to the 5th one, since the liquid isn't filled to the top, you know.
から、た行の5個目と、で、ば行の、これ上から2個目だね。び。で、た行の1番下、た。で、た行の、下から2番目、てで、飛び立てだ！
So, the 5th of the "ta" row, and the 2nd from the top in the "ba" row: "bi". Then the very bottom of the "ta" row: "ta". And the 2nd from the bottom of the "ta" row: "te". Together, it's "Tobitate"!
やったあ、すごーい！ちょっと待って女子君ごめん、小代に解かんなかった。女子君がさ、答え書いてくれてたから、分かっちゃった！やったあ！
Yay, amazing! Wait, sorry Joshi-kun, Koyori couldn't solve it. Joshi-kun wrote the answer for me, so I figured it out! Yay!
え、3問解けました？解けた？ぴこぴぽ？やったあ！ということで、え、お題に該当する歌声を届けよってことだから、
Huh, did we solve all 3? Did we solve them? Piko-pipo? Yay! So, it says "Deliver a singing voice corresponding to the theme,"
ギターを使う曲、ケモノになる曲、飛び立つ曲を歌えばいいってことですね！
which means we just have to sing a song using a guitar, a song about beasts, and a song about flying away!
やったあ！みんなありがとう。女子君さすがこよりの女子君、助けてくれますね。え、じゃあこの3曲歌えば、試練クリアできるってこと？え、なんかね、試練をクリアしたら
Yay! Thank you everyone. Joshi-kun, as expected of Koyori's Joshi-kun, always helping out. Wait, so if I sing these 3 songs, I can clear the trial? Wait, if we clear the trial,
なんとですね、あれをお披露目できるみたいですよ、女子君！
apparently we can reveal that, Joshi-kun!
手錠も外れたあ！外れたよお！
My handcuffs came off too! They came off!
え、もうちょっと手錠遊びたかったんだけどな。ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと時間あるから。ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっとつけて、ちょっとつけてください。つけられます？つけられます？
Aw, I wanted to play with the handcuffs a bit more. Wait, we have a little time. Can you please put them back on me?
負けました。
I lost.
妖怪にマジで不安だったんだよ。
I was seriously scared of the Yokai.
不安だったんだよ。
I was really scared.
ねぇ手錠よかったのに、あ、つけられたかな？つけられましたか？
Hey, my handcuffs were fine... Ah, did I get put in them? Were they attached?
ついたー！やった！
They're on! Yay!
やったじゃねえんだよ。
Yay, my foot!
これを取るために今頑張ってたんだ。
I've been working so hard to get these off.
え、あ、どう、ど、どうかなどし君。
Um, ah, how, how is it, Doshi-kun?
あ、ちょっと、ちょっと下から煽りとかやってみます。あ、待って、なんかギターある！
Ah, let's try some low-angle teasing. Wait, there's a guitar!
今気づいた！今気づいた！
I just noticed! I just noticed!
ギターありました！ギター！おもっ！
There's a guitar! A guitar! It's heavy!
ありました！ギター！でこれをね、使って歌、歌うってことですね。
There it is! A guitar! So we use this to sing, right?
これヒントだったってことだよな。
So this was a hint, huh?
なるほどな。
I see.
よいしょ、お、おもちゃんです。おもちゃんです。
Heave-ho, oh, they're toys. They're toy ones.
え、でちょっと、え、何？どう、どういうのがいい？
Um, and wait, um, what? What kind is good?
繋がってない、繋がってない。
They're not connected, they're not connected.
見て見て見て！こんなに、こんなにね、ほっそい！
Look, look, look! They're so, so thin!
ほっそいのに繋がってんでしょ。ちゃんと繋がってんでしょ。
Even though they're thin, they're connected, right? Properly connected, right?
え、どし君に囚われちゃった……！
Ugh, I've been captured by Doshi-kun...!
はずかしい！
How embarrassing!
どう、どうして？どし君、これに手錠なんてつけるよ……！
Why, why? Doshi-kun, putting handcuffs on me like this...!
ねぇ！
Hey!
早くライブしろ！
Hurry up and do your live!
早くライブし、はい。
Hurry up and live, yes!
さあ！じゃあね、せっかく曲も……曲はね、まだみんなには分かってないと思うんだけど。
Now then! Since we've got the song... you guys probably don't know the song yet, though.
こよりの頭の中にはこれを歌おうってやつがもう浮かんでっているので、その3曲を歌いたいと思います！
But inside Koyori's head, the songs to sing are already popping up, so I want to sing those 3 songs!
それじゃあ早速歌いにいくぞ！
Well then, let's go sing right away!
まあどうやってこの手錠は外す？
Well, how do I take off these handcuffs?
星空見上げ 私だけのヒカリ教えて
Gazing at the starry sky, tell me my own unique light
あなたはいまどこで 誰といるのでしょう?
Where are you now, and who are you with?
楽しくしてるコト思うと さみしくなって
When I think about you having fun, I feel so lonely
一緒に観たシネマひとりきりで流す
Playing the cinema we watched together all by myself
大好きなひとが遠い 遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
The person I love is so far away, so far that I want to cry
あした目が覚めたら ほら希望が生まれるかも Good night!
When I wake up tomorrow, maybe hope will be born, Good night!
I still I still I love you!
I'm waiting waiting forever
とまらないのよ Hi!!
I just can't stop! Hi!!
眠りのふちで ユメがくれる想い出の One day
At the edge of sleep, one day of memories that dreams bring
あなたの言葉には 少しウソがあった
There was a little lie in your words
離さないよとキミだけだと 抱きしめたのに
Though you hugged me tight saying you'd never let go and that I was the one
約束がフワリと暗い夜に消えた
Our promise gently vanished into the dark night
大好きなひといつも いつまでも探してしまう
I'll always and forever search for the person I love
きっと目が覚めても まだ幻を感じたい morning
Even when I wake up, I want to still feel the illusion this morning
I lost I lost I lost you!
You're making making my music
もう逢えないの? No!
Can't we meet again anymore? No!
大好きなひとが遠い 遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
The person I love is so far away, so far that I want to cry
あした目が覚めたら ほら希望が生まれるかも
When I wake up tomorrow, maybe hope will be born...
ほら希望が生まれるかも Good night!
Maybe hope will be born, good night!
大好きなひとが遠い 遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
My beloved person is far away, too far, it makes me want to cry
きっと目覚めても
Surely, even when I wake up,
まだ幻を感じたい morning
I still want to feel the illusion, morning
I still I still I love you!
I'm waiting waiting forever
とまらないのよ Hi!!
It won't stop, hi!!
I still I still I love you!
I'm waiting waiting forever
まだ逢えるよね? ね!!
We'll meet again, right? Hey!!
素晴らしき世界に今日も乾杯
A toast to this wonderful world today as well
街に飛び交う笑い声も
Even the laughing voices flying around the town
見て見ぬフリしてるだけの作リもんさ
Are just fabrications where we turn a blind eye
気が触れそうだ
I feel like I'm going mad
クラクラするほどの良い匂いが
A scent so good it makes me dizzy
ツンと刺した鼻の奥目を覚ます
Pierces sharply deep in my nose, waking my eyes
本能のまま今日は誰の番だ?
Following instinct, whose turn is it today?
この世界で何が出来るのか
What can be done in this world?
僕には何が出来るのか
What can I do?
ただその真っ黒な目から
From those pitch-black eyes,
涙零れ落ちないように
So that tears won't overflow and fall
願う未来に何度もずっと
In the future I wish for, over and over again,
喰らい付くこの間違いだらけの世界の中
I keep biting into this world full of mistakes
君には笑っていてほしいから
Because I want you to keep smiling
もう誰も傷付けない
I won't hurt anyone anymore
強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become stronger and stronger
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can stay being me
素晴らしき世界は今日も安泰
This wonderful world is safe and sound today as well
街に渦巻く悪い話も
Even the bad rumors swirling around the town
知らない知らないフリして目を逸らした
I ignored them, pretending not to know anything
正気の沙汰じゃないな
It's not in our right mind
真面目に着飾った行進
A procession dressed up in all seriousness
鳴らす足音が弾む行き先は
The destination where our echoing footsteps bounce
消えない消えない味が染み付いている
Has a lingering, unerasable taste soaked into it
裏側の世界
The world on the reverse side
清く正しく生きること
To live purely and righteously
誰も悲しませずに生きること
To live without making anyone sad
はみ出さず真っ直ぐに生きること
To live straight without standing out
それが間違わないで生きること?
Is that living without making mistakes?
ありのまま生きることが正義か
Is living just as you are justice?
騙し騙し生きるのは正義か
Is living while deceiving justice?
僕の在るべき姿とはなんだ
What is my proper form?
本当の僕は小物なんだ
The real me is just small fry
教えてくれよ
Teach me
今日も答えのない世界の中で
Today too, in a world without answers,
願ってるんだよ不器用だけれど
I am wishing, clumsy though I may be
いつまでも君とただ笑っていたいから
Because I just want to laugh with you forever
跳ねる心臓が身体揺らし叫ぶんだよ今こそ動き出せ
My beating heart shakes my body and shouts, "Now is the time to move!"
弱い自分を何度もずっと
Over and over again, my weak self,
喰らい付くこの間違いだらけの世界の中
I keep biting into this world full of mistakes
君には笑っていてほしいから
Because I want you to keep smiling
もう誰も泣かないよ
No one will cry anymore
強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become stronger and stronger
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can stay being me
ただ君を護るそのために
Just to protect you,
走る走る走るんだよ
I'm running, running, running!
僕の中の僕を超える
To surpass the me inside of me
消える飛行機雲
A fading vapor trail,
僕たちは見送った
We watched it depart.
眩しくて逃げた
Dazzled, I ran away.
いつだって弱くてあの日から
Always weak, ever since that day,
変わらずいつまでも変わらずにいられなかったこと
Unable to remain unchanged forever...
いつまでも変わらずにいられなかったこと
No matter how much time passed, we couldn't stay unchanged...
悔しくて指を離す
Frustrated, I let go of your fingers.
あの鳥はまだうまく飛べないけど
That bird still can't fly very well yet,
いつかは風を切って知る
But someday she'll know how to cut through the wind.
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place we cannot reach is still far in the distance,
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
And I just gaze at it, hiding my wish.
子供たちは夏の線路歩く
Children walk along the summer railroad tracks,
吹く風に素足をさらして
Baring their bare feet to the blowing wind.
遠くには幼かった日々を
In the distance are the days of our youth,
両手には飛び立つ希望を
And in both hands, hopes that leap forth.
消える飛行機雲
Fading vapor trails,
追いかけて追いかけて
Chasing, chasing them.
この丘を越えた あの日から変わらず
Ever since we crossed that hill, without change,
いつまでも
Forever and ever,
真っ直ぐに僕たちはあるように
So we may always walk straight ahead,
わたつみのような強さを守れるよきっと
Surely we can protect a strength like the deep blue sea.
あの空を回る風車の羽根たちは いつまでも同じ夢見る
The windmill's blades rotating in that sky always dream the same dream.
届かない場所をずっと見つめてる 願いを秘めた鳥の夢を
Gazing forever at the unreachable place, dreaming the bird's secret dream.
振り返る
Looking back,
焼けた線路覆う入道雲
The sun-baked tracks are covered by storm clouds,
形を変えても
Even if their shapes change,
僕らは覚えていてどうか季節が残した昨日を
May we remember the yesterdays the seasons left behind.
消える飛行機雲
Fading vapor trails,
追いかけて追いかけて
Chasing, chasing them.
早すぎる合図 ふたり笑い出してる
A signal given too early, we burst into laughter.
いつまでも真っ直ぐに 眼差しはあるように
So we can always look straight ahead,
汗が滲んでも 手を離さないよずっと
Even if sweat trickles down, I'll never let go of your hand, forever.
消える飛行機雲 僕たちは見送った
Fading vapor trails, we watched them go.
眩しくて逃げた いつだって弱くて
Dazzling and fleeting, we were always so weak.
あの日から変わらず いつまでも変わらずに
From that day on, unchanged, forever and ever unchanged,
いられなかったこと 悔しくて指を離す
Frustrated that I couldn't stay, I let go of your fingers.
はい、ごめんなさい、なんか、ミュート芸になってしまったみたいで、
Um, I'm sorry, it seems like I accidentally went on mute,
えー、ちょっと今、この状態になっちゃってるんですけれども、
um, so right now, I'm in this kind of state,
えー、今ですね、えー、これでき、
um, but right now, um, with this,
試練を乗り越えられたということで、
having overcome the trial,
アイドル衣装をお披露目できる状態になったので、
I'm now in a state where I can reveal my idol outfit,
えー、あの方が待っているライブ会場に行ってアイドル衣装をお見せしちゃいたいと思います。
so I want to go to the live venue where that person is waiting and show off my idol outfit!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
曲がりくねった 道の先に
At the end of the winding road,
待っている 幾つもの 小さな 光
many small lights await.
まだ 遠く て 見え なく て も
Even if it's still too far to see,
一歩 ずつ ただ それ だけ を 信じてゆこう
I'll just take it one step at a time and believe in that.
全てを 愛せ なく て も
Even if I can't love everything,
ありのまま の 心 で
with an honest heart,
何 か を ただ 一つ だけ 愛し続けてる人
the person who keeps on loving just one thing...
その 誇らしげ な 顔 に は
On that proud face,
何 に も 負け ない ほど 大きな 優しさ が 溢れ出してる
overflows a tenderness greater than anything else.
曲がりくねっ た 道の先に
At the end of the winding road,
待っている 幾つもの 小さな光
many small lights await.
まだ 遠く て 見え なく て も
Even if it's still too far to see,
一歩 ずつ ただ それ だけ を 信じてゆこう
I'll take it one step at a time, just believing in that.
握りしめ た 手のひら じゃ 何に も 掴めやしないし
With clenched fists, you can't grasp anything at all,
瞳を閉じれば ふと蘇る歌があって
When I close my eyes, a song revives,
心はどんな時でも あの頃へ戻れると呟いていた
whispering my heart can return to those days.
いつか手にしたままの 夢や憧れの種が
The seeds of dreams and longings I once held in my hands...
僕にだけ気付いて欲しいそうに 明日へと目を凝らしてる
...are straining their eyes toward tomorrow, as if wanting only me to notice them.
逃げ出してきた 昨日よりも 昨日よりも
More than yesterday, more than yesterday when I ran away,
ぶつかり合った 今日をにこぼした涙
the tears I shed today after bumping into each other...
立ち止まった 自分を連れて あの日の僕に
...bring my stopped self back to meet the me of that day,
会いにゆこうか
shall I go meet him?
まだりくねった 道の先に
Far ahead on the still winding road...
見据えさせて 震い立たせる
...let me fix my gaze and rouse myself.
まだりくねった 道の先に 幾つもの小さな光
Far ahead on the still winding road, countless small lights...
まだ遠くて 見てたくって
...are still far away, yet I want to see them.
一歩ずつ ただそれだけを
Step by step, just that alone...
正しさという狭い出口で くれない想いが僕を震い立たせる
...unrequited feelings of so-called righteousness rouse me up.
振り返れば ただまっすぐに 伸びていた今日までの辿る足跡
Looking back, the footprints leading up to today stretched out so straight.
まだりくねった 道の先に 夢見てたあの日の
Far ahead on the still winding road, the me of that day I dreamed of...
待っているから
...is waiting for me, so I'll go.
みなさん先輩 この先輩！来てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone, senpais! Thank you so much for coming!
こよりちゃん？
Koyori-chan?
はい！
Yes!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ちょっと あの3人揃ったんで
Since the three of us are gathered here...
かなりあで、ステ、いい？ あ、じゃあやっちゃおう！
...can we do "Kanaria"? Let's do it!
せーの！かなリアです！やったー！
Ready, set! We are "Kanaria"! Yay!
え、ちょ、衣装可愛いね！あ、そう、衣装可愛いでしょ！
Your outfit is so cute! Yeah, isn't it cute?
後ろのしっぽも見たい！
I wanna see the tail in the back!
見たい見たい！めっちゃ可愛い！
Me too! So cute!
なんかリボンから、ほら、Tボーンから生えてるみたい！
It looks like it's growing right out of a T-bone!
しっぽ短いから見づらいけど後ろ緑なんだよ！
The tail's short so it's hard to see, but the back is green!
全然見えなーい！首惜しーい！
I can't see it at all! So close!
え、このさ、曲をさ、あのカナリアで歌いたいなって思った理由があって
Um, the reason why I wanted to sing this song with Kanaria...
実はこより、小さい頃から自分のこ、こぶくろになってくれる人を探してたんです
...actually, since I was little, I've been looking for someone to be my Kobukuro.
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
どういうこと？そういうこと！こぶくろを探してた！
What do you mean? Just that! I was looking for a Kobukuro!
この曲すごい好きで、こぶくろになってくれる人いないと1人で全部歌えなくって
I love this song so much, but I couldn't sing it all by myself without a Kobukuro!
こぶ、あ、僕たちこぶくろということ？
Kobu... Wait, do you mean us two are Kobukuro?
そう！あの、あやかさん、こぶくろさん！
Yes! Ayaka-san, Kobukuro-san!
じゃあ僕たち2人で組んでいきましょう！
Then let's team up together!
ここで生まれたか、かなリア！
Born right here, Kanaria!
このへんにね、あ、このへんにこよりがいるということで
Koyori is supposedly around here, so...
3Dの姿を手に入れて、な？
having gotten her 3D form, you see.
また3Dのときにね？
And when she's in 3D, right?
いるよ！
She's here!
いるよ！みんなここにこよりがいるからね？
She's here! Koyori's right here, you know!
本物の、後で、探してくださいね！
The real deal! Go look for her later, okay?
いやいや、ちょっと、これどうすればいいの？これこうすればいいのか？
Wait, what am I supposed to do? Do I do it like this?
いるよ！こよりどこでもいいんだ、これこうすればいいのか？いるよ！
She's here! Koyori is-- wait, do I do it like this? She's here!
取れた、やっと取れたー！
I got it, I finally got it!
いーいーいーいー！や、やっと取れたー！
Yay yay yay yay! Ah, I finally got it!
やーい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
あ、そうそう、こよりにね？
Oh right, for Koyori, you see...
だめだめ、そっち行ったら。次の指令が来ているんですよ。
No, no, don't go that way. There's a new directive.
指令？
A directive?
まだあるんですか？そう、衣装ね、もらったからってね、終わりじゃねえんだ。
There's more? Yeah, just because you got the outfit doesn't mean it's over, you know.
終わりわけないだろ。ということで、次の場所に行く指令が来ているので、そこに行ってください！
Of course not. So a directive to go to the next location has arrived, please go there!
え？わ、お、お、お疲れ様でした。私たちとももうお別れです。
Eh? W-W-W-Well done. It's time to part ways with us too.
え、うそー！楽しんでね？
Eh, no way! Have fun, okay?
まだまだ、まだだぞ！じゃあ、いくよ！
There's still more, still more! Okay, here we go!
せーの！いぇーい！
Ready, set! Yay!
指令書に書いてあるところに来たけど、ここ、いったいどこなんだ？なんかさ、ミシ...
I came to the place written in the directive, but where on earth is this? It's like, a mis--
試練...
Trial...
恐怖を乗り越えて助手くんを笑顔にしろ
Overcome your terror and make Joushi-kun smile.
初めてのバイオハザードVRをプレイすべし！
Play your first Resident Evil VR!
いやあのこよバイオハザードめっちゃ好きになったんですけど、いや、でもVRはたぶんめっちゃ怖いと思うんで、やってきてなくて、いや絶対無理！無理無理無理無理！やですやです無理です！
I mean, Koyori became a huge fan of Resident Evil, but, you know, VR is probably super scary, so I haven't done it, and no way! No way, no way, no way! I don't want to, I don't want to, no way!
いやです！いやです！いやです！無理です！うわあ！付けられたー！
I don't want to! I don't want to! I don't want to! No way! Whoa! It's on me!
ということで、無理やりVRゴーグルをつけられたこよは、みんなを笑顔にするために試練に挑むことに。
And so, Koyori, having been forced to put on VR goggles, sets out on a trial to make everyone smile.
始まります！うわー、緊張する。え、セブンの最初...
It's starting! Whoa, I'm nervous. Eh, the start of Seven...
あ！あこれもしや、ミアの映像。あ、あ、元気？
Ah! Oh, could this be Mia's footage? Ah, ah, how are you?
みあ、ありがとう。
Mia, thank you.
うそなんでしょ？
That's a lie, right?
あー、ミア！
Ah, Mia!
探そう！探さな...探したくないけど探す！イーサンはそういう男だから、こよは探せないけど多分、怖いから。
Let's find her! I gotta find-- I don't want to find her, but I will! Ethan is that kind of guy, so Koyori can't really find her, but probably, because she's scared.
すげえ生い茂ってる！え、すごい！
It's so overgrown! Whoa, amazing!
怖い！ここ...ここはまだ怖くなかったはずなんだよな。
Scary! Here... this place shouldn't have been scary yet.
え！びっくりした！
Eh! That startled me!
イーサンの手だ！あー、虫が飛んねえね。
Ethan's hand! Ah, bugs are flying around.
昔のプレイを思い出しながら、イーサンと一緒にミアを探しに来たこよ。
Recalling her past playthrough, Koyo came to look for Mia together with Ethan.
今日は時間の都合上、残念ながら前篇をお見せできないため、ここからは助手くんにたくさんのこりうむをお届けします！
Today, due to time constraints, unfortunately we can't show you the first part, so from here on we'll deliver lots of Koyolium to Joushi-kun!
やだー、やめよう！
No way, let's stop!
あ、こわい！こわい！むり！
Ah, scary! Scary! No way!
早くつけてイーサン！懐中電灯お前も持っててしね！
Put it on fast, Ethan! You hold the flashlight too, damn it!
ここ開けられないんだよね。あ、最初あれ開けらん...
Can't open this place. Ah, can't open that first one...
あ、違う！うわ！これは自分の手にびびってます。
Ah, no! Whoa! I'm getting startled by my own hand.
すごい覗く！すご、足すくむ...
Peeking so much! Wow, my legs are freezing up...
あ、あ、あ、あ...
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
あー！あー！あー！
Aah! Aah! Aah!
ああ！殺される！
Ah! I'm gonna be killed!
あー！
Aah!
VRやべえ！
VR is crazy!
あ、ここじゃなかったっけ。
Ah, was it not here?
うわあ！
Whoa!
ミア、お前を助けに来たのにどうして...
Mia, I came to save you, why...
どうして...イーサンガード！
Why... Ethan guard!
怖い！ここじゃなかったっけ？あー！
Scary! Wasn't it here? Aah!
怖い、ここじゃなかったっけ！
Scary, wasn't it here?!
あー！
Aah!
あ、弾薬少なっ！待って待って弾薬があと一個しかない！
Ah, ammo is so low! Wait, wait, I only have one ammo left!
ミア、撃て、撃てた！ミアごめんね！
Mia, shoot, I shot! Mia, I'm sorry!
え、待って、うわあ！
Eh, wait, whoa!
最愛のミアとの死闘を繰り広げ、なんとか倒すことができたこよさんだったが...
Having fought a life-or-death battle with her beloved Mia, Koyo-san somehow managed to defeat her, but...
お前も家族だ...あ、ジャックおじさん！
"You're family too..." Ah, Uncle Jack!
あー殴られたー！
Ah, I got punched!
マルグリットおばさん？マルグリットもあったっけ？お前も家族になるんだよ！
Aunt Marguerite? Was there Marguerite too? "You're gonna be family too!"
マルグリットおばさんに捕まったり助けられたりしてたこよさんは...
Koyo-san, who kept getting caught and saved by Aunt Marguerite...
ジャックおじさんから逃れようと必死に逃げまどい...
Desperately running away to escape from Uncle Jack...
行けた！行けた行けた行けた！行くぞ！
Made it! Made it, made it, made it! Let's go!
マルグリットおばさんとの勝負に挑むことに。相棒の場所を覚えている...
Decides to challenge Aunt Marguerite. Remembering the partner's location...
俺が？いや、そんな場合じゃない。お前死ぬぞ！
Me? No, this isn't the time. You're gonna die!
お前死ぬぞ。お前死んじまうぞ。どこから出てくるか質問に答えろ！
You're gonna die. You're gonna die. Answer the question about where they come from!
言ったって信じるわけないさ。いや話を聞け！
You wouldn't believe me if I told you. No, listen to me!
おい、シャッターを閉めるんだ！
Hey, close the shutter!
やめろ！うわあ！
Stop it! Whoa!
くそっ
Damn it!
うおおお！
Whoa!
行けおじさん！うぇーい！
Go, old man! Woo!
車で追え！
Chase him with the car!
おいおい行け！やったやったぞやったぞ！
Hey, hey, go! We did it! We really did it!
ここまでやれば大丈夫じゃない？
If we go this far, shouldn't we be fine?
うそ！上にいんの！？
No way! He's upstairs?!
やめて！おじさん！
Stop it, old man!
やめてー！
Stop it!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
これおじさんの車！すごーい！触れる？
This is the old man's car! Amazing! Can I touch it?
あ触れる！触れてるよ！触れてないよ！ぎゃあ！おじさん！おじさん！
Ah, I can! I'm touching it! No, I'm not! Kyaa! Old man! Old man!
もう終わりにしよう、俺たちで。
Let's put an end to this, together.
やめろ！やめろ！
Stop it! Stop it!
やめろ！痛いー！
Stop it! It hurts!
やった。
We did it.
おじさん！おじさん起き上がるよ！？
Old man! Old man, you're getting back up?!
ああおじさん！その平然と起き上がりやがって！どうしてくれるんだよこのクソ野郎が！
Ah, old man! Acting all casual as you get back up! What do you think you're doing, you asshole!
うそおそおそ！あ！あ！あ！あ！
No, no, no! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah!
うわあ！マジで！うわあ！
Whoa! Seriously! Whoa!
あ、おじさん一時期やったと思ったが
Ah, I thought I got the old man for a moment, but
これなら、これならもう大丈夫だろ。
if it's like this, this should be fine now.
はあ、おじさんいい顔してんな。
Haah, old man, you've got quite a face.
初めての女子組も笑顔になってくれたから、やっぱVRやったことあってもこわー！
Even though it's my first time as a girl giving me a smile, even with VR experience, it's so scary!
やったよ！女子組ー！
We did it! Girls!
いいぞガード。
Nice guard.
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、ということでバイオハザードVRおわせていただきましたー！
Yes, so that was Resident Evil VR!
いやあ、すでにプレイしてたからまだできたけどこれ初プレイだったらだめだ、死んどる。
Man, I already played it so I managed, but if this were my first time, no way, I'd be dead.
はい、ということでね、今のはものすごいかいつまんだものだったんですけれども、どこかで何かしらの形でねちょっと長いバージョンも公開しようと思っているので、それもぜひ見てください。
Right, so that was an extremely summarized version, but we're planning to release a longer version somewhere in some form, so please check that out too.
ほ？試練をクリアしたので、なんと！ライブ会場でまた別のアノ人柄待ってるかもしれません。
Huh? Since we cleared the trial, what if! Another person might be waiting for us at the live venue.
だって！よーし、じゃあ急いでいかなくチャー！行くよー！
Because! Alright, then we gotta hurry! Let's go!
昔々そのまた昔
Long, long ago, in a time beyond memory,
とある貴族の仲良し兄弟
there lived a close pair of aristocratic siblings.
ちゃんとやれ！
"Do it properly!"
ぢいやが呼ぶ席につけ よーいどん！
Called by the butler, take your seats, ready, go!
ナイフとフォークで応戦いたしますの
We engage in combat with knife and fork.
だって僕らはブルジョアの 立派な立派な貴族様なんですの
After all, we are proud and proper bourgeois aristocrats.
ひれ伏せ愚民 君との違いを
Bow down, commoners, witness the difference between us.
ヴァイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
Viceroy, we'll show you!
おいうぇ、まってまってまって勝手にそんな見抜けるようなハッタリかまして
Hey, wait, wait, wait, making up such transparent bluffs on your own—
はーい はーい はい はい お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
Yes, yes, right, right, as big brother commands (lol).
ああむかつくぜ まーぢむかつくぜ
Ah, it pisses me off, it seriously pisses me off.
兄に対して生意気な態度
Such a sassy attitude towards your older brother!
鳴の音ゴングを鳴らせ ケンカ勃発で宣戦布告
Ring the gong, declare a full-scale battle!
悪戯して 悪ノリして ほらほら煽ってStyleで ほらほら煽ってStyleで
Playing pranks, getting carried away, teasing and provoking in style!
“大安売り” 買っちゃったなら 毎度ありがとう
If you bought it at a "massive clearance," thanks as always—
お貴族様の負け！
Your loss, aristocrat!
拙い 引き出しと 駆け引きの駆け引きでキメる
Settling it with clumsy drawers and clever bargaining.
兄の威厳見せるため 痛倒する
To show an older brother's dignity, taking them down.
興奮してる お前の身体 おれを誰だと思ってる
Your body is all excited—who do you think I am?
おれさまが絶対王政
I am absolute monarchy!
生まれながらにしてチート お呼びじゃない人生がスタート
Born a cheat, a rejected life begins.
当然です 見てみな優緒はガチ勢
Naturally, look at Yuu, total hardcore gamer.
ハイ論破 ハイ論破 ハイ論破 もらってくぜVサイン
High logic, high logic, high logic, taking the V-sign!
はーい はーい はい はい はなまるよくできました☆
Yes, yes, right, right, well done with a gold star☆
ああむかつくぜ まーぢむかつくぜ
Ah, it pisses me off, it seriously pisses me off.
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ とっておきを 君に見舞え
Running your mouth at me, I'll give you my absolute best!
報復！制裁！挑発しちゃって 意地悪して 一枚上手
Retribution! Sanction! Provoking me, being mean, staying one step ahead!
チャンスは貰ってくスタンスで
Taking every chance with that attitude.
痛恨ミス！お生憎様ね 君の負け！
Fatal mistake! Too bad for you, your loss!
だけどキミ キミだけが ボクに似合いのライバル
But you, only you are my fitting rival.
オチルのも 凹んでんのも 調子狂わせられるから
Falling or getting depressed throws off my rhythm,
今宵もてめーと やいやいやい
so tonight too, with you, yadda yadda yadda!
大体兄様がいつもそうやってナヨナヨしてるから僕が兄様の分まで積極的にやってやってるんだよ
Big brother is always so indecisive, so I'm just taking the initiative for his share too!
分かってないやつなんだよ もう少し感謝してほしいね
You just don't get it. I want you to show a little more gratitude.
年上のくせに全然頼りにならないお兄様とか
Even though you're older, you're a totally useless big brother...
いやもう何も言うな！今日から僕が兄ね、これ決定！ハイ決定！
Don't say a word! Starting today, I'm the big bro, decided! High decision!
あーもううるせぇ！
Ah, so noisy!
まーじでまーじでムカつくぜ
Seriously, seriously, so irritating.
憎まれ口はおくちはチャックと
Keep your snarky mouth zipped shut.
時の声をゴングを鳴らせ
Ring the gong at the call of the times.
次世代エンペラーはこの僕だ！ 俺だ！
The next-gen emperor is me!
見てくれだけワル風にして
Making yourself look like a bad girl.
ほらほら被ってくStyleで ほらほら
Hey hey, wearing that style, hey hey.
見せかけだけのスキルじゃ物足りません
Surface-level skills just aren't enough.
まいどありがと まさかの二重人格
Thanks as always, what a surprising dual personality.
こよこねぇさー！
Koyo-koneezan!
バイオの恐怖に耐えたことで巫女ねえさんとお歌を歌うことができました！
By enduring the horror of Resident Evil, I got to sing with Miko-neesan!
いやぁ、良かったねぇ、ニャンハロー！
Man, that's great! Nya-hello!
こよとみこねぇで並ぶのは初めてだね 初めてです、しかも！
It's our first time side by side, Koyo and Miko! Our very first time!
お兄様ばかりのアイドル衣装です！
In idol outfits with lots of big brothers!
めっちゃシナジーないですか、色合い！
Don't they have great color synergy?
めっちゃねピンクでね、アイドルっぽーい！
Super pink and so idol-like!
いやぁありがとうございます来てくれて！ エリートが、登場してやったよ！
Thanks so much for coming! Elite has arrived!
そのねえさんとね、ちょっと殴り合いしてみたいだったんですよ。
I wanted to have a little fistfight with that neesan.
え、なんで？ え、なんか楽しいかなって思って！
Eh, why? Eh, just thought it'd be fun!
違う違う、エリートねえさを…！
No, no, Elite Neesan...
エリートねえさんを世界で唯一ずっとおめぇてくれるもんな、こよはね。
You're the only one in the world who pampers Elite Neesan, Koyo.
そう、こよはねえさん大好きですからね。ピロピロピロ…
That's right, Koyo loves Neesan. Piro-piro-piro...
じゃあちょっと記念写真とか取りました？ あじゃ、ハートとか？ ねぇねぇねぇさん、あれ？
So did you take a commemorative photo? Ah, hearts? Hey hey, Neesan, huh?
やった！かわいい！パシャパシャパシャ…！
Yay! So cute! Snap snap snap...!
はい、じゃあちょっと時間も短いんですけど！
Alright, our time is a bit short though!
この後こよりラボに換えるんで、みこさんもよかったら一緒に来ないですか？
We're heading to Koyori's Lab next, would you like to come along, Miko-san?
え、みこも？ お菓子とか用意して…、え、お菓子の用意したよ！
Eh, Miko too? Prepared snacks... Eh, I prepared snacks!
なんか、蹴られたぁ！ ぜぁ、ただいまー！
Somehow, I got kicked out! Aaah, I'm back!
なんかみこねぇさん蹴ってどっか行っちゃったー！
Miko-neesan kicked me and went somewhere!
ということでラボに帰ってきましたよ！ はい、のアイドル衣装ね、お披露目しようと思っていたところではちょっとミュートの事故が起きてしまいまして
And so we're back in the lab! Yes, we were going to reveal the idol outfits, but a mute accident happened...
これも生だからということで、あ、ちょっと完全になっちゃってごめんなさい！
That's live for you, so sorry it got completely messed up!
でも見てくれてみんなありがと！ というわけで今からなんと、5つお知らせをさせていただきます！
But thank you everyone for watching! So now, I have 5 announcements to share with you!
まず一つ目は、博衣こよりからの挑戦状！
First is the challenge from Hakui Koyori!
なんとですね、この1周年記念配信全体に謎が散りばめられておりました！
Apparently, riddles were scattered throughout this 1st-anniversary stream!
その謎を解いて概要欄のURLのサイトへ行こう！
Solve them and check the URL in the description!
契約リングネックレス！
Contract ring necklace!
こよのしっぽをイメージしたデザインになっています！
It's designed with Koyori's tail in mind!
大きめなのでネックレスとしてもいいし、
It's quite big, so you can wear it as a necklace,
指輪としてもはめられるし、可愛いケースも付けました！
as a ring, and we've included a cute case too!
そしてお出かけに使ってねな、エコバッグ！
And for when you go out, an eco-bag!
ポイントは使いやすいデザインとしっかりした生地、そしてめちゃカワな女宿くんの顔ケースです！
The highlights are the easy-to-use design, sturdy fabric, and super cute Juk-kun face case!
カラビナがついていて、キーホルダーみたいにカバンにつけることもできますよ！
It has a carabiner, so you can attach it to your bag like a keychain!
さらに、お出かけには欠かせないよねな、ハンドタオル！
And of course, a must-have for outings, a hand towel!
老若男女に関係なく使えるデザイン、しっかり水分を吸収してくれる肌触りのいい生地になっています！
It's designed for anyone regardless of age or gender, with soft fabric that absorbs moisture well!
ハンドタオルって何枚あっても持っておきたいですもんね！
You always want to have multiple hand towels!
そして、要望の多かったシステムボイスのセットを遂に販売いたします！
And finally, we are releasing the much-requested system voice set!
目覚ましボイスやパソコンのオンオフ用ボイスなど充実しておりますので是非使ってください！
It's packed with alarm voices and PC on/off voices, so please use them!
さらに、全部セットで買っていただいた方には直筆サインと
And for those who buy the full set, a handwritten signature
複製メッセージ入りポストカードと特典ASMRボイスをプレゼント！
and message postcard, plus a bonus ASMR voice!
ASMRのボイスは観覧車の中で契約リングをこよがプレゼントした時のシチュエーションになっています！
The ASMR voice is a situation where Koyori gifts you the contract ring inside a Ferris wheel!
そして直筆サイン、全員に書きます！書きます！
And I'll write handwritten signatures for everyone! I will!
メッセージはですね、白押しにさせていただきました！
The message... I had it foil-stamped!
ぜひ購入して、うわっ沢山書かれてるやばいやばいと嬉しい悲鳴を上げさせてください！
Please purchase it and let us hear your happy screams at how much is written!
そして4つめのお知らせ！
And the fourth announcement!
このあと21:30からメンバー限定アフターパーティを行います！
Starting at 21:30 tonight, we'll hold a members-only afterparty!
コメントを拾いつつ、事故もありましたのでアイドル衣装をマジマジと見たりとか
While picking up comments, since there were some incidents, we'll take a close look at the idol costume, etc.
ヘッドセットが実あのこよりオリジナルものになっておりまして見づらいんですけど、こちらをご紹介させていただいたりとか
The headset is actually Koyori's original one, it's hard to see, but I'll introduce that, etc.
着たかったけど着るタイミングがなかった水着になんかよくわかんないけど着替えたりしますので
or change into a swimsuit I wanted to wear but didn't have the chance to,
ぜひ遊びに来てください！
so please come play!
そして最後5つめが重大告知です！
And finally, the fifth is a major announcement!
今から博衣こより2曲目のオリジナル曲を歌って踊っちゃいます！やったー！
Starting now, I'll sing and dance to Hakui Koyori's 2nd original song! Yay!
曲を作っていただいたのはナナホシ管弦楽団さん！すごく可愛い曲を仕上げていただきました！
The song was made by Nanahoshi Kangenrakudan! They finished a super cute song for me!
こちらの曲配信終了すぐに3Dで撮影したMVを公開いたします！
Right after this stream ends, we will release the MV filmed in 3D!
みんなにも踊ってもらいたいダンスなので3DダンスMVにしましたよ！是非見てください！
It's a dance I want everyone to do, so we made it a 3D dance MV! Please check it out!
さらに本日24時からは各サイトにて音源販売されますのでぜひゲットしてください！
And starting at midnight today, the sound source will be sold on various sites, so please get it!
それでは新曲歌います！
Now, let's sing the new song!
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.!!
Otome yo motomeyo Q.E.D.!!
知りたいな 君はさ
I want to know, what do you
僕のことをどう思う？
think of me?
僕はね 君のことを あとは宿題
As for me, what I think of you... is homework for later!
ラブ・ラボ 引きこかっちゃうな
We'll hole up in the lab,
聞かなきゃってほら愛してる
gotta ask, you see, I love you!
論より証拠主義です
It's evidence over theory,
前進あるのみ！ねぇ
moving forward is all there is! Hey,
少し手伝って
lend a little hand
人類の課題
with humanity's problem!
好き好き好き好き好き好き好き好き
Love, love, love, love, love, love, love!
答え合わせしましょう
Let's compare our answers,
見付かっちゃ
found you!
魔法の公式
The magic formula
化学反応してるよね僕ら
is having a chemical reaction between us,
問題はまだまだまだまだ未解決！
and the problem is still totally unsolved!
証明中 恋の予想
Proving our love's forecast,
物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね
we're even adding to the laws of physics!
これぞ天才だ！
That's true genius!
あの子よりその子よりもっと言ってちょうだい
Tell me more than that girl or anyone else!
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.!!
Maiden, seek it out, Q.E.D.!!
Question やっぱりさ さっきから僕のこと見てたよね？
Question: Were you watching me this whole time?
Question 見てない？じゃあ僕が君のこと
Question: You weren't? Then what about me—?
どぎまぎパラダックス
Flustered by the paradox,
慌てちゃって葛藤中
panicking and conflicted,
宇宙も秘密主義じゃ
even the universe is secretive—
ビッグバン！
Big Bang!
ねえ君とふたり 人類の終わり
Hey, just the two of us, the end of humanity,
好き好き好き好き好き好き好き
love, love, love, love, love, love, love,
∞未来でしょ
an infinite future!
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.!!
Maidens, seek it out, Q.E.D.!!
魔法の公式
The magic formula.
惹かれ合うたび不思議なレポートは
Each time we're drawn together, this mysterious report
進行形 まだまだまだまだ未提出
is a work in progress, still unsubmitted!
(ドヤ！) 設計中
[Hah!] Currently in design.
DNA 君の細胞 書き換えちゃうもんでね
DNA, rewriting your very cells, you see!
これぞ天才だ！
This is true genius!
どの子よりどの子よりずっと(好き、って)言ってるじゃん！
Saying "I love you" way more than anyone else!
乙女よ求めよ急げQ.E.D.!!
Maidens, seek it out, hurry, Q.E.D.!!
ねぇ、僕らふたり 人類の終わりに
Hey, the two of us, at the end of mankind,
割り切れなかった 余りだったら
if we were an unresolvable remainder—
ねぇ、少し手伝って 人類の課題
hey, help me out a bit with humanity's problem!
好き×好き×… 答え合わせしましょう？
Love x love... Shall we compare our answers?
見つけちゃうもん！
I'll find it!
魔法の公式 化学反応してるよ ねぇ
The magic formula is causing a chemical reaction, hey—
僕ら 問題は
our problem is
まだまだまだまだ未解決 (ドヤ！)
still completely unsolved! [Hah!]
証明中 恋の予想 物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね (どうだ！)
Proving love's forecast, rewriting the laws of physics! [How's that?!]
これぞ天才だ！どの子よりどの子より ずっと(好き、って)言ってちょうだい
This is true genius! Please tell me "I love you" more than anyone else!
乙女よ求めよ求めよ急げQ.E.D.!!
Maidens, seek it out, hurry, Q.E.D.!!
3.1415926535897932384626433832795028841977??
3.14159265358979323846264338327950288419...
Q.E.D.!!
みんな、ふたりで見に来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for coming to see us!
そして1周年ありがとう！
And thank you for our 1st anniversary!
いやめちゃんめちゃんこのダンス難しいんでドキドキした！
Man, this dance is super difficult, so my heart was pounding!
Q.E.D.スタンプいっぱいつかってくれてありがとね！
Thank you for using all those Q.E.D. stamps!
え、このあとエンディングもありますし、え、おとみよ、もとめよQ.E.D.の、え、MV発表もありますので、それもぜんぶ見てください！
There's an ending after this, and the MV for "Otome yo Motomeyo Q.E.D." too, so check it out!
本当に本当にありがとう！
Really, truly, thank you!
2周年、2周年じゃねえわ、2年目もよろしくお願いします！
For our 2nd anniversary—wait, not 2nd, please look forward to our 2nd year too!
助手くん大好きだよ、うーん、ま！
Assistant-kun, I love you! Mwah!